<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<missions>
	<mission>
		<type>Center Scenario</type>
		<number>1</number>
		<name>Close Quarters</name>
		<specialRules>
			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a circular zone on their opponent&apos;s side of the board while their warcaster/warlock is within a zone.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Kill Box
			Mark two zones (8&quot; diameter circles) in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of each player&apos;s turn, starting on the second player&apos;s second turn, a player earns 1 control point by controlling the zone on his opponent&apos;s side of the board while his warcaster or warlock is within a zone.
		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>
			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than the opponent wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone on your opponent&apos;s side of the board.
		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-center-close-quarters.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Center Scenario</type>
		<number>2</number>
		<name>Gauntlet</name>
		<specialRules>
			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone on the opponents side of the board.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Kill Box
			Mark two 6&quot; x 8&quot; zones in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn, a player earns 1 control point if he controls the zone on the opponents side of the board.
		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>
			The first player to earn at least 2 control points and have more control points than the opponent wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone on your opponent&apos;s side of the board.
		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-center-gauntlet.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Center Scenario</type>
		<number>3</number>
		<name>Overrun</name>
		<specialRules>
			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone in the center of the board.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Kill Box
			Mark a 36&quot; x 8&quot; zone in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn, either player can earn 1 control point by controlling the zone.
		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn 2 control points immediately wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-center-overrun.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Distant Scenario</type>
		<number>4</number>
		<name>Guidons</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to move an objective into a zone or control/destroy their opponents objective.
			Mark two zones (4&quot; diameter circles) and place two objectives (Guidon Bearer) in accordance with the diagram below.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn:
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;a player earns 1 control point when his objective is not contested by an enemy model and is within the zone on his own side of the board&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;OR (cannot score both ways in one turn)&lt;/strong&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 2 control points when he controls or destroys his opponents objective.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than the opponent immediately wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within zones.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-distant-guidons.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Distant Scenario</type>
		<number>5</number>
		<name>Supply and Demands</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control/destroy objectives and control a zone on their opponent&apos;s side of the board
			Mark two zones (12&quot; diameter circles) and place two objectives (Fuel Cache) in accordance with the diagram below.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives
			At the end of each player&apos;s turn, starting on the second player&apos;s second turn:
			- a player earns 1 control point if he contests the zone on his opponent&apos;s side of the board while he controls the objective on his own side of the board.
			OR (cannot score both ways in one turn)
			- a player earns 2 control points if he controls the zone on his opponent&apos;s side of the board and the objective within that zone is destroyed.		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than the opponent wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone on your opponents side of the board.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-distant-supply-and-demand.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Distant Scenario</type>
		<number>6</number>
		<name>Destruction</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to destroy two objectives on the opponents side of the board.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives
			Before deployment, position an objective (Monolith) on both OBJ1 positions in accordance with the diagram below. When an objective in the OBJ1 position is destroyed place a new objective (Monolith) in the OBJ2 position on the same side of the board during the next maintenance phase using the rule of least disturbance (WARMACHINE Prime, p.65) if necessary.
			Players earn 1 control point for each objective that is destroyed on their opponents side of the board.		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn 2 control points immediately wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory&amp; Tiebreakers, For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within 4 of an objective on your opponents side of the board.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-distant-destruction.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Dual Scenario</type>
		<number>7</number>
		<name>Incursion</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control two flags.
			Place three flags in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of the second players first turn, randomly remove one flag from the board.
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn, a player earns 1 control point for each flag he controls.		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than the opponent immediately wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within 4 of a flag.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-dual-incursion.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Dual Scenario</type>
		<number>8</number>
		<name>Process of Elimination</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control two zones.
			Mark two 6&quot; x 14&quot; zones in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn, a player earns 1 control point for each zone that he controls. Players can only earn 1 control point per turn. Players can only earn 1 control point in each zone during the game.		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to score 2 control points and have more control points than his opponent wins the game. If both players reach 2 control points on the same turn re-open scoring in both zones and play until a player earns 2 more control points. Repeat as needed.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within zones.bby.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-dual-process-of-elimination.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Dual Scenario</type>
		<number>9</number>
		<name>Outflank, Outfight, Outlast</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control two zones.
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Reinforcements
			Mark two zones (12&quot; diameter circles) in accordance with the diagram below.
			At the end of each players turn, starting on the second players second turn, a player earns 1 control point for each zone that he controls. you		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than the opponent, immediately wins the game.
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in Victory &amp; Tiebreakers. For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within zones.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-dual-outflank-outfight-outlast.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Flank Scenario</type>
		<number>10</number>
		<name>A Flag Too Far</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control two flags. 
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Reinforcements 
			Place four flags in accordance with the diagram below.  
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn: 
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 1 control point if he contests his secondary flag while controlling his primary flag &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;If either player controls their primary and secondary flags, they earn an additional control point. &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 control points and have more control points than his opponent, immediately 
			wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in 
			&quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, only counts the army points within 4&quot; of the primary flags. 					</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-flank-a-flag-to-far.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Flank Scenario</type>
		<number>11</number>
		<name>Bunkers</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone. 
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Reinforcements 
			Mark two zones (8&quot; diameter circles) in accordance with the diagram below. 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, player 1 earns 1 control point if 
			he controls zone P1; player 2 earns 1 control point if he controls zone P2.  		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 2 control points and have more control points than the opponent, immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in 
			&quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, player 1 only counts the army points within zone P1; player 2 
			only counts the army points within zone P2.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-flank-bunker.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Flank Scenario</type>
		<number>12</number>
		<name>Envelopment</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone. 
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Reinforcements 
			Mark a two 14&quot; x 6&quot; zones in accordance with the diagram below. 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, player 1 earns 1 control point if 
			he controls zone P1; player 2 earns 1 control point if he controls zone P2. 		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn 3 control points immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as 
			outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, player 1 only counts the army points within zone 
			P1; player 2 only counts the army points within zone P2.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-flank-envelopment.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Objective Scenario</type>
		<number>13</number>
		<name>Demolition</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control an objective and a zone on the opponent's side of the board. 
			Center an objective (Explosives Cache) and mark two zones (8" diameter circles) in accordance with the 
			diagram below.  
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn: 
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 1 control point if he controls the zone on his opponent's side of the board.  &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 1 control point when he controls the objective. &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 Control Points and have more Control Points than his opponent, immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers&quot;.  For the 3rd tiebreaker, only count the army points within the zone on your opponent's side of the board or within 4&quot; of the objective. 		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-objective-demolition.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Objective Scenario</type>
		<number>14</number>
		<name>Incoming</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control/destroy objectives and control a zone on their opponent's side of the board. 
			Mark two zones (14&quot;x6&quot; rectangles) and place two objectives (Artillery Emplacement) in accordance with the diagram below.  
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn: 
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 1 control point if he controls the objective on his own side of the board. &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;OR (cannot score both ways in one turn) &lt;/strong&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A player earns 2 control points if the objective on his opponent's side of the board is destroyed and he controls the zone on his opponent's side of the board.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 Control Points and have more Control Points than his opponent, immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers&quot;.  For the 3rd tiebreaker, only count the army points within the zone on your opponent's side of the board. 		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-objective-incoming.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Objective Scenario</type>
		<number>15</number>
		<name>Restoration</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to destroy an objective on their opponent's side of the board and control a zone. 
			Mark a zone (14&quot;x6&quot; rectangle) and place two objectives (Restoration Cache) in accordance with the diagram below.  
			&lt;strong&gt;Artifice:&lt;/strong&gt; Interactive Objectives 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, a player earns 1 control point if the objective on his opponent's side of the board is destroyed and he controls the zone		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 3 Control Points and have more Control Points than his opponent, immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers&quot;.  For the 3rd tiebreaker, only count the army points within the zone		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-objective-restoration.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Radial Scenario</type>
		<number>16</number>
		<name>Command and Control</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone while contesting any flag with their warcaster or warlock. 
			Mark one zone (12&quot; diameter circle) and place four flags in accordance with the diagram below. In this scenario, in addition to the normal control requirements for control zones, a player must contest any flag with a friendly warcaster or warlock in order to control the zone. Players do not earn control points for controlling flags in this scenario. 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, either player can earn 1 control point for controlling the zone. 		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn 2 control points immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone. 		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-radial-command-and-control.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Radial Scenario</type>
		<number>17</number>
		<name>Diversion</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a flag while contesting a zone on their opponent's side of the board. 
			Mark two zones (8&quot; diameter circles) and place two flags in accordance with the diagram below. Each player may only score on the flag to his right. In this scenario, in addition to the normal control requirements for flags, a player must contest the zone on the opponent's side of the board in order to control his designated flag. Players do not earn control points for controlling zones in this scenario. 
			At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, either player can earn 1 control point for controlling his designated flag. 		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn at least 2 control points and have more control points than the opponent immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within 4&quot; of a flag.		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-radial-diversion.jpg</map>
	</mission>
	<mission>
		<type>Radial Scenario</type>
		<number>18</number>
		<name>Sacrifice</name>
		<specialRules>			&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; Players attempt to control a zone while a friendly model is B2B with a flag. 
			Mark one zone (12&quot; diameter circle) and place one flag in accordance with the diagram below. In this scenario, in addition to the normal control requirements for zones, a player must own a friendly model in B2B with the flag in order to control the zone. Players do not earn control points for controlling flags in this scenario. At the end of each player's turn, starting on the second player's second turn, either player can earn 1 control point for controlling the zone. 
			Each turn after scoring is complete, but before the next turn begins, all models in B2B with the flag,owned by a player who scored that turn, suffer a POW 20 magic damage roll and are pushed 3&quot; directly away from the flag and knocked down. 		</specialRules>
		<victoryConditions>			The first player to earn 2 control points immediately wins the game. 
			If time runs out before a player has won the game via scenario or assassination victory, break the tie as outlined in &quot;Victory &amp; Tiebreakers.&quot; For the 3rd tiebreaker, count only the army points within the zone. 		</victoryConditions>
		<map>images/maps-radial-sacrifice.jpg</map>
	</mission>
</missions>
