<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<pages>
	<page>
		<title>SR 2012 Information</title>
		<anchor>information</anchor>
		<content>
							&lt;p&gt;
					In Steamroller tournaments, players face off in a series of games and pit their skills against a gauntlet of opponents to determine who will emerge victorious. Steamroller is ideal for groups of 8 to 64 players and promotes fast and furious play while stressing the ability to adapt to a variety of scenarios.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Player Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Logistics&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players participating in a Steamroller 2012 (SR2012) event must bring all their own models, stat cards, dice, measuring devices, markers, and templates they require for play. Tokens representing in-game effects such as focus, fury, spells, and abilities are required and must be kept adjacent to the corresponding model on the table. Players should also bring a copy of the SR2012 scenario reference sheet for use during the tournament.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Army Lists&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players must bring two legible copies of all their army lists complete with point costs. Army list point totals cannot exceed the point size chosen for the game and cannot fall more than 2 points under the point size chosen for the event. Players must incorporate all bonus warjack or warbeast points in their army list(s) point total. A 50-point Kaelyssa army, for example, must include 55 to 57 points of models.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players can bring a second list if they choose. All lists must be led by warcasters/warlocks from the same faction. Mercenary players can use different contracts or Theme Forces for their lists. Minion players can use different pacts or Theme Forces for their lists. Players cannot include the same version of a model or unit with FA:C in more than one list. The original and epic incarnation(s) of a character do not count as the same version of a model. Any player-determined model relationships (attached, client, marshaled, etc.) must be specified in the list and cannot change between rounds.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 contains scenarios that use reinforcements. Reinforcements are additional models added to a player&apos;s army list(s) only for scenarios that have the reinforcements artifice. These models and their points must be shown on a player&apos;s army list(s) in case a reinforcements scenario is played. Detailed rules for reinforcements are found in the Artifices section (p. 9)
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 allows all released Theme Forces to be used. Anyone using a Theme Force must have the Theme Force available for the event organizer&apos;s reference (in order to verify the army list) and for the opponent&apos;s reference (in order to view the Theme Force&apos;s special rules). Permission is hereby granted to photocopy the Theme Forces section from the WARMACHINE and HORDES expansion books as well as any Theme Forces appearing in No Quarter Magazine for personal, non-commercial use only and subject to the terms found within those original source materials.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Modeling and Painting&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						All models used in Privateer Press organized play events must be Privateer Press miniatures from the WARMACHINE or HORDES ranges. The miniatures must be fully assembled on the appropriately sized base for which the model was designed. Any non–Privateer Press models, unassembled miniatures, or inappropriately based models are not permitted.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Models that have not yet been released to the general public at the time of the event are not permitted unless those models are readily available at the event venue (such as convention-release models in tournaments at that convention). The Extreme versions of models are perfectly acceptable for use in organized play.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Privateer Press encourages players to have a fully painted force on the table. Games with painted armies are more interesting to watch and generally enhance the experience for all. Although painting is not required, players should take this chance to show off all aspects of the hobby. 
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Model Conversions&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Playing with a uniquely individualized and painted force is one of the most rewarding aspects of the hobby.Just as with information disclosure and sportsmanship, players are expected to be unambiguous about model representation. The following rules must be adhered to when using converted models in organized play.  These rules are meant not to limit a player&apos;s modeling options but rather to allow creativity without generating an environment that could become confusing during game play. At his discretion, an event organizer can make exceptions to these rules to approve any reasonable conversion.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;
						A converted model must contain a majority of parts from the WARMACHINE or HORDES model for which the rules were written. For example, a Testament of Menoth conversion must be composed mostly of parts from the Testament of Menoth model. The end result of any conversion must be clearly identifiable as the intended miniature and accurately represent its weapons and equipment as listed in its rules. Any conversions must beclearly pointed out to your opponent before the game to avoid confusion.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;
						On warrior models, converting and swapping weapons is acceptable provided the new weapon represents the same type of weapon replaced (like swapping one sword for another). Anything relating to a weapon&apos;s	specific rules must be maintained to avoid confusion on the tabletop. For example, a weapon with Chain Weapon must still be modeled as a chain-style weapon, and a weapon&apos;s length must be considered when converting weapons with Reach.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;
						Weapons cannot be swapped on warjack and warbeast models. Since many of the &apos;jacks and beasts utilize the same chassis or torso, the weapons are the most identifiable part of the model when looking across the tabletop. Converting warjacks and warbeasts is still encouraged, but the aesthetics of the weapons must be maintained. Modifying weapons is permitted, as long as the end result is easily identifiable as the intended warjack or warbeast&apos;s proper weapon.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;
						The models with &quot;upgrade kit&quot; blisters are an exception to the standard conversion rules. Because the parts in these blisters define an entirely separate model for rules purposes, all parts must be clearly visible on the model for legal tournament use. For example, a helljack with one claw and one harpoon is not Malice. The model must have the correct head, harpoon blade, and all three spirit parts from the Malice upgrade kit inorder to be considered Malice.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;
						Miniatures must be on their appropriately-sized WARMACHINE/HORDES base, but scenic details can be added. The base&apos;s perimeter must always be considered when modeling scenic details. While it is acceptable for scenic elements to overhang the base&apos;s edge, the base itself and not the scenic elements is used for all measurements. The edge of a model&apos;s base must not obscured to the point that accurate measuring becomes difficult or impossible.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Sportsmanship&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						A fair and honest in-game environment is required in order for everyone to have fun. Players must accurately execute the rules of the game and fully cooperate with opponents to honestly answer any questions that arise before and during the game. Players are also responsible for holding their opponents to the same standards.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The event organizer will not be able to observe every game. If your opponent is doing something that is making you uncomfortable—stalling, bending the rules, or outright cheating—tell your opponent about it. Explain what he can do to remedy the situation in order to maintain a fair, honest, and fun in-game environment. If the behavior continues or a dispute arises, call the EO and explain the situation. The EO always has the final word on rules questions or debates. Players must accept all rulings made by the EO whether or not they agree.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players must present a mature and polite demeanor to their opponents and the EO. Failure to do so will result in immediate disqualification. An EO can also disqualify a player for any incident that is deemed unsporting. This includes, but is not limited to, offensive or abusive conduct, bullying, cheating, constant rules arguments, improper play, stalling, and other inappropriate actions. Disqualified players are not eligible for any awards or prizes and are barred from further participation in the event and any other related events.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Occasionally circumstances will prompt a player to concede a game during a tournament. Concessions are not recommended since there is almost always a chance for victory. In the case of a concession, the winning player will be awarded a win, half the control points (rounding up) for a scenario win and army points destroyed based on an assassination using current board conditions. The player who conceded will receive a loss and no points in any category. An EO can disqualify a player from a tournament if a concession is deemed unsportsmanlike.
					&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Event Organizer Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Schedule&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						When estimating the overall length of a tournament, an EO should add extra time for each round to cover the variable, allow time to do pairings, get people to their new tables, and get the next round started.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Number of Rounds&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The event will run until one player has more tournament points than any other player at the end of a round. Once this condition is met, the event ends without additional games.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players participate in a timed format with all players participating in every round. The number of players participating in the tournament determines the maximum number of games usually required to determine a winner.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;table&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Players&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Rounds&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;8 or fewer&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3-round event&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;9 to 16&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;4-round event&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;17 to 32&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5-round event&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;33 to 64&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6-round event&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;65 to 128&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;7-round event&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;First Round Pairings&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Shuffle all the tournament record sheets together. Take the top two sheets and set them to one side. This gives you the first pairing. Without shuffling the pile again, remove the next two sheets and repeat the process until all players have an opponent. If you have an odd number of players, see ?Byes &amp;Odd Number of Players? below.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Once you have completed the pairings, note the opposing player&apos;s ID on each player&apos;s sheet to track that player&apos;s opponents. Record the tournament point and control point scores for each player when the round ends. Ignore the subtotal boxes for now; they only matter for rounds after the first.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Subsequent Pairings&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						From here on, all pairings and ranks are based on tournament point subtotals and pairings from previous rounds. After all games in the previous round have been completed, sort the tournament record sheets into piles based on the number of tournament points. Shuffle each pile.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Take the top sheet of the pile with the greatest number of tournament points and choose the first opponent in the pile he has not already played. Set this pair aside and repeat the process. When you reach the end of a pile move to the next pile. If a pile has an odd number of players, pair the last player against someone from the next-highest tournament point pile. Do not do this with any individual player more than once per event. Again, once you have all the pairings, write the opposing player&apos;s name in the appropriate column on each player&apos;s sheet. It might take several attempts to find pairings that avoid duplicating match-ups.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Some EOs use additional criteria for their pairings. Keep in mind that any additional criteria must come after matching players with the same number of tournament points who have not already played one another.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Byes &amp;Odd Number of Players&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Steamroller games take place between two players. In the case of an odd number of players, one player will receive a bye. A player receiving a bye sits out of the current round and receives 1 tournament point, half the control points (rounded up) for a scenario win, and half the army point level (rounded up) for the event.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The EO will randomly determine which player receives the bye if a tournament begins with an odd number of players. In subsequent rounds, the EO will randomly select a player from those with the lowest tournament point totals. The EO should ensure that the same player does not receive a bye more than once per event.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Game Timing&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;table&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Event Point Size&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base Round Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Turn Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Extension Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;70&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Each round in a Steamroller event has a variable round length. Before each round begins, the EO rolls a d3 and multiplies the result by the variable, the turn extension length for the event size. He then rolls a d6 to determine whether the variable will be subtracted from (on a result of 1–3) or added to (on a result of 4–6) the base round length (shown above) to determine the overall round length.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						During rounds that use scenarios with the reinforcements artifice, the EO will add two extensions to the overall round length after the variable is subtracted or added. In this case do not exceed the maximum round length of base round length plus three extensions. The EO will not announce the result of this roll or reveal the amount of time remaining in a game to players.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Adjustments to Rounds Using Reinforcements	&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;table&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Event Point Size&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Reinforcements &lt;br&gt; (Points)&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Player Timing &lt;br&gt; (Per Player)&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;NA&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
					&lt;table&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Variable Roll&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Overall Round Length&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;-3&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base -1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base +1 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+1&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+2&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;+3&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						After the time for a round has expired, the EO calls ?dice down.? If a player is in the process of moving a model, he finishes that movement, then the turn and game end. If the player is in the process of making a roll of any kind, he completes that single roll, then the turn and game end. If the roll is an attack roll that directly hits its target, resolve the direct hit damage roll as well.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						At dice down, resolve all end-of-turn effects that would occur including the removal of models if applicable. Models that have not entered play yet or were removed from the table do not enter play and do not count as destroyed.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Dice down or assassination prompts a final iteration of scenario scoring even though the game is over. Assassination victories always take priority over a scenario win.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						If a game does not have a clear winner after dice down, check the scenario for how to determine the winner. Before the tournament begins the EO should instruct all players how the tiebreaker system works, as described in the SR2012 scenario reference sheet.			
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Turn Timing&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Steamroller also uses a timed turn length to ensure a fair play environment. Players in each game use a timer to track the fixed amount of time available for each turn. This time limit is based on the point size of the event. A player&apos;s timer begins after the resolution of continuous effects.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						If a player is executing a model/unit&apos;s normal movement when his turn time expires, he finishes moving that model/unit, then his turn ends. If the player is in the process of making a roll of any kind after movement is complete, he completes that single roll, then his turn ends. If the roll is an attack roll that directly hits its target, resolve the direct hit damage roll as well.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						When a player moves a model, rolls dice, or takes significant time to make decisions during the other player&apos;s turn, the player whose turn it is has the option of stopping the clock while these actions are resolved.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Turn Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Once per game, each player can extend his turn length with an extension. A player can extend his turn length by declaring he is doing so during his turn. After the current turn time expires, the active player&apos;s opponent resets the clock for the turn extension, then the active player continues his turn. Extensions cannot extend a turn past the total round time.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						During rounds that use scenarios with the reinforcements artifice, each player is granted a second extension. The second extension is the same duration as a normal extension and cannot be combined with another extension on the same turn.
					&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Scenarios&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Scenario Selection&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;				
						Steamroller 2012 contains six groups of scenarios. The scenarios in each group have similar objectives. In order to ensure that tournaments contain a variety of different scenario types, EOs must select a scenario from each group before they can choose from the same group again.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;table&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Round&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Group Choices Available&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Group Chosen&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2, 3, 4, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2, 3, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The EO should choose scenarios before a tournament to ensure they have the required materials for those scenarios. The selected scenarios can be played in any order. The random scenario table below can also be used.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Scenarios cannot be repeated in a standard tournament. All players play the same scenario each round. The EO keeps the upcoming scenario secret until the start of each round of games.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						During each round the EO should provide at least one copy of the scenario being played for every four players (every two tables) in the event. After declaring the scenario, the EO will read the rules for that scenario aloud. The EO should answer questions concerning the scenario before the round begins. Players are responsible for making sure they understand the scenario.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						EOs should stress that it is imperative all players pursue both the scenario and assassination victory conditions during the game as players do not know when the round time is going to expire.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;table class=&quot;tinyTable&quot;&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;D6 Roll: Group\D3 Roll: Scenario&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;1 - Center&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Close Quarters&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Gauntlet&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Overrun&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;2 - Distant&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Guidons&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Supply and Demand&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Destruction&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;3 - Dual&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Incursion&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Process of Elimination&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Outflank, Outfight, Outlast&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;4 - Flank&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;A Flag Too Far&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Bunkers&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Envelopment&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;5 - Objective&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Demolition&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Incoming&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Restoration&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
						&lt;tr&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;6 - Radial&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Command and Control&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Diversion&lt;/td&gt;
							&lt;td&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/td&gt;
						&lt;/tr&gt;
					&lt;/table&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Deployment&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 adds flank scenarios that use flank deployment as illustrated in the diagram below. Distances that are measured from a player&apos;s board edge or back of deployment zone can use a point on the board edge as indicated here.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;img src=&quot;images/deployment-flank.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flank Deployment Scenario&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 also contains radial scenarios. Mechanics that are measured from a player&apos;s board edge or back of deployment zone can use a point on either of the two board edges indicated below
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;img src=&quot;images/deployment-radial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flank Deployment Scenario&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						In order to mitigate the initiative advantage of the first player, the deployment zones in SR2012 are different sizes based on turn order.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						In standard and flank deployment, the first player has a 7&quot; deployment zone (13&quot; AD) and the second player has a 10&quot; deployment zone (16&quot; AD). Theme Force bonuses do not alter the width of flank deployment zones.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						In radial deployment, the first player has a 17&quot; deployment zone (23&quot; AD) and the second player has a 20&quot; deployment zone (26&quot; AD).
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Terrain&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Terrain is a key element for games of WARMACHINE and HORDES. Terrain pieces should present choices to both players but should not give an undue advantage to either. To reinforce this principle, terrain should be relatively symmetrical on a table. For example, if one side of the board contains a forest, a hill, and a linear obstacle then the other side should contain terrain that provides concealment, elevation, and cover as well.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						As a general rule, an average table should contain five to seven pieces of terrain placed close enough to eliminate large open areas without unduly constricting movement. The size of terrain pieces is also important.  No piece should be insignificantly small or extremely large; terrain pieces that range from 4? to 8? in length and width are best.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The type, number, and placement of terrain pieces are up to the EO, but the following guidelines must be followed when setting up tables:
							&lt;ul&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Do not place terrain within deployment zone areas. This does not apply to Advance Deployment areas.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;All terrain pieces must be placed at least 3? away from other terrain pieces. This includes terrain pieces granted by Theme Force bonuses.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Do not place impassable terrain within zones when playing scenarios that use them. Note that all other terrain types can be placed within the zones.&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						EOs can choose whether to fully represent the zones presented in the scenario packet with templates or mark the corners of rectangular zones or the center point of circular zones. If center or corner markers are used, players can measure the zone whenever it is relevant to fulfilling scenario conditions. Any attempted abuse of this rule is grounds for disqualification. If a scenario zone marker is inadvertently moved during play, pause the clock and reset the zone marker&apos;s position. If scenario scoring occurred while a marker was in an incorrect position the control points stand, even if this error is noticed after the fact.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Artifices&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 introduces artifices to scenario play. Artifices are mandatory additional rules present in certain scenarios.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h5&gt;Kill Box&lt;/h5&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Starting on the first player&apos;s second turn, if a player ends his turn with a friendly warcaster/warlock within 10? of any board edge, that warcaster/warlock is destroyed.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h5&gt;Reinforcements&lt;/h5&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Reinforcements are additional models, up to a specified point value (see p. 29), added to a player&apos;s army list(s) that are used only in scenarios with the reinforcements artifice. These models are separate from the main part of each list and must be included, with battlegroup/marshal affiliation if applicable, even though reinforcements scenarios might not be played. Reinforcements follow the normal Field Allowance rules for their corresponding list. Players can field reinforcements without using all of the reinforcement points available. Reinforcements must follow the restrictions of any Theme Force to which they are added and benefit from any applicable bonuses (including Field Allowance) but are not counted toward satisfying tier requirements.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Warcasters, Warlocks, models/units with the Pre-Deployment or Attached rule, and models/unit that cannot begin the game in play cannot be reinforcements. Reinforcement models cannot be bonded. Reinforcements lose the Ambush ability. Reinforcements with the Prey ability choose their Prey target after both players are deployed. During the maintenance phase, on a player&apos;s second turn or later, these models can be placed within 3? of any point on the reinforcements line shown in the scenario diagram. All of a player&apos;s reinforcements must be placed on the same turn.				
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Adjustments to Rounds Using Reinforcements
						&lt;/p&gt;

					&lt;h5&gt;3. Interactive Objectives&lt;/h5&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Replace the basic objective properties listed in the scenario reference sheet with the objective card type (p. xx) indicated in the scenario.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Starting the Game&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players can ask to see their opponent&apos;s lists at any time, including before list selection, before the start of the game, and during play. A player must take care not to disrupt the flow of the game while doing this. All models in each list must be presented to an opponent upon request before list selection.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						After the pairings and scenarios for the game have been announced but before the starting roll, each player secretly chooses one of his lists and conceals the card for the selected warcaster or warlock on the table. A player cannot change lists after making this selection. Both players reveal their lists simultaneously.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Both players roll a d6 for the starting roll. The player with the higher result can choose to be the first or second player. The second player chooses his table edge. The first player deploys first and takes the first turn. The EO has the option to predetermine table sides for players in order to save time during deployment.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h4&gt;Final Standings&lt;/h4&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Players score tournament points based on the outcome of each game. A player gains 1 tournament point for a win and 0 for a loss or draw. Tournament points determine a player&apos;s current standing in a tournament.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						In the case of two players with the same number of tournament points, determine which one ranks higher by calculating strength of schedule.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Count the tournament points scored by each opponent of the tied players to determine strength of schedule.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						The player whose opponents have the highest total score has the best strength of schedule score and earns the higher rank. If strength of schedule is the same for both players, the player who accrued the most control points throughout the tournament earns the higher rank. If control points are also the same for both players, the player who accrued the most enemy army points destroyed throughout the tournament earns the higher rank. When counting destroyed army points, use the destruction scoring rules found on p. 36.
					&lt;/p&gt;
		</content>
	</page>
	<page>
		<title>SR 2012 Scenario Refernce Sheet</title>
		<anchor>refernce</anchor>
		<content>
			&lt;h2&gt;Scenario Glossary&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Starting number&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					The number of models that a model/unit starts with based on the point cost paid. Models that are discounted always use their card’s listed point cost and model count for scoring. Models that are free also use the card’s point cost and model count for scoring. If a free model/unit does not begin the game in play, use the lowest point cost on the card to determine the model count required for scoring.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Own&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Players own the models in their fielded army list and any models created by abilities of models in the army list.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Control&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					See Zone, Flag and Objective.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Contest&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					A player must own at least one model within a zone, within 4&quot; of a flag, or within 4? of an objective to contest that zone, flag, or objective. Inert warjacks, wild warbeasts, models that are fleeing or out of formation, and models a player owns that are under the control of an opponent cannot contest.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Zone&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					A player controls a zone if he owns one or more models within it and no opponent contests it. Ignore inert warjacks, wild warbeasts, models that are fleeing or out of formation, and models a player owns that are under the control of an opponent when checking for control. There are no additional requirements for warcasters, warlocks,  warjacks, or warbeasts.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					For a unit to control a zone the unit must contain 50% or more of its starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must be within the same zone.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					For a solo to control a zone, it must have an army point cost of 1 or more. For solos that consist of multiple models, divide the point cost of the solo by the model count on the card to see if each model is worth at least 1 point. For multiple-model solos to control a zone they must contain 50% or more of their starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must be within the same zone.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Reinforcements&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					During the Maintenance Phase, on a player’s 2nd turn or later, these models can be placed within 3? of the reinforcements line shown in the scenario diagram.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					All a player’s reinforcements must be placed on the same turn.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					If a warjack controlled by a warcaster is a reinforcement model, during the focus allocation step of the Control Phase following its placement as a reinforcement it is allocated 3 free focus points. This focus cannot exceed the normal focus allocation limit. If a warbeast controlled by a warlock is a reinforcement model, on the turn
					following its placement as a reinforcement it can be forced while outside its controlling warlock’s control area.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Flag (40 mm base)&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					All flags are models with the following qualities:
				&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Incorporeal, stationary models&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Immune to all in-game effects&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Do not activate&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Cannot be targeted, damaged, moved, placed, or removed from play&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					A player controls a flag if he owns one or more models B2B with a flag that an opponent does not contest. When checking for control conditions ignore inert warjacks, wild warbeasts, models that are fleeing or out of formation, and models a player owns that are under the control of an opponent. There are no additional requirements for warcasters, warlocks, warjacks, or warbeasts. If the model B2B with the flag is a member of a unit, the unit must contain 50% or more of its starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must also be within 4? of the flag.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					If the model B2B with the flag is a solo it must have an army point cost of 1 or more. For solos that consist of multiple models, divide the point cost of the solo by the model count on the card to see if each model is worth at least 1 point. For multiple-model solos to control a flag the solo must contain 50% or more of its  starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must also be within 4? of the flag.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Objective (50 mm base)&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4&quot; of an objective that an opponent does not contest.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Objectives also follow the individual rules defined on their &lt;a href=&quot;objectives.html&quot;&gt;objective rules cards&lt;/a&gt;. Objectives are considered friendly models to all other models.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Kill Box&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Starting on the first player’s 2nd turn, if a player ends his turn with a friendly warcaster/warlock within 10? of any board edge, that warcaster/warlock is destroyed.
				&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Victory and Tiebreakers&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Assassination Victory&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					When only one player owns warcasters/warlocks remaining in play, that player immediately wins the game. Conduct control point scoring upon an assassination victory. This scoring does not change game results (that is, it cannot lead to a scenario victory) but affects the final standings. If all warcasters/warlocks are simultaneously destroyed, the game ends and victory is determined according to tiebreaker conditions.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Scenario Victory&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					When a player has fulfilled the victory conditions described in the scenario, that player immediately wins the game.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;1st Tiebreaker&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					If time runs out before a player has won the game, the player who owns the most warcasters/warlocks remaining in play wins the game. If both players own the same number of warcasters/warlocks in play, check the 2nd tiebreaker to determine the winner.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;2nd Tiebreaker&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					The player who has the most control points wins the game. If both players have the same number of control points, check the 3rd tiebreaker to determine the winner.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/h3&gt;
				Tally the army point value of the models/units owned by each player within the area designated by the scenario. Ignore inert warjacks, wild warbeasts, and fleeing models when checking 3rd tiebreaker conditions. The player with more army points in the designated area wins the game. If both players have the same number of army points in the designated area, check the 4th tiebreaker to determine the winner.
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Warcasters/Warlocks: 5 points for each warcaster or warlock (regardless of warjack and warbeast bonus points) within the scoring area. If a warcaster or warlock choice consists of multiple models, all the models with the warcaster or warlock subtype must be within the scoring area. Models automatically included with the warcaster or warlock choice without the warcaster or warlock subtype do not affect warcaster/warlock scoring.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Warjacks/Warbeasts: Points equal to the army point cost of the model within the scoring area.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Units and Unit Attachments: Points equal to the unit’s army point cost. Ignore units that have fewer than 50% (rounding up) of their starting number remaining in play when counting army points. At least half (rounding up) of the remaining models must be within the scoring area. Models with the Attachment ability add to the unit’s value and also add to the number of models needed. For example, ten Long Gunners need five or more models in play to be worth 10 points, and twelve Long Gunners including their unit attachment need six or more models to be worth 12 points.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Solos: Points equal to the army point cost of the model within the scoring area. If a solo choice consists of multiple models, when counting army points ignore solo choices that have fewer than 50% (rounding up) of their starting number remaining in play. All those remaining models must be within the scoring area for the solo choice’s value to be counted.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/h3&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Tally each player’s army points that have been destroyed or removed from play as described below. The player whose opponent suffered more army points destroyed/removed from play wins the game.
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Models/units are worth their army points value.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Units below 50% of their starting number (rounding up) are worth 50% of their army points (rounding up) including all attachments.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Inert warjacks and wild warbeasts are worth their full army point value.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Warcasters and warlocks are worth 5 army points each.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Scenario Scoring - Exceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				All the standard rules for scenarios are contained within the SR2012 scenario reference sheet above. Models that do not conform well to these general guidelines are listed here with answers to the commonly asked questions as they pertain to scenarios.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;				
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Lesser Warlocks
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes (Either model can control a zone/flag)&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: All lesser warlocks are worth 2 points. Companion warbeasts included with these models are worth the Lesser Warlock’s PC minus 2.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: All lesser warlocks are worth 2 points. Companion warbeasts included with these models are worth the Lesser Warlock’s PC minus 2.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Light Warjacks/Warbeasts without a PC
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 5 Army Points&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 5 Army Points&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Solos without a PC
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 Army Points&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 Army Points&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Kallus’ Feat (Incubi)
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N), 3rd Tiebreaker, 4th Tiebraker&lt;/strong&gt;: At the end of your opponent’s turn, group all remaining created Incubi into groups of 5 and the remainder into another group of X, which counts as X remaining from a group of 5. Each of these groups now counts as a purchased Incubi solo and follows the standard scenario rules for multiple-model solos.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Feralgeist
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: If controlling a friendly warbeast use the warbeast’s point cost. If controlling an enemy warbeast place Feralgeist in B2B contact with the controlled warbeast, using the rule of least disturbance (WARMACHINE: Prime Mk II, p.65) if necessary, then remove the warbeast from play.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 Army Point&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Machine Wraith
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: If controlling a friendly warjack use the warjack’s point cost. If controlling an enemy warjackplace Machine Wraith in B2B contact with the controlled warjack, using the rule of least disturbance (WARMACHINE: Prime Mk II, p.65) if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 Army Point&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Multiple model solos that do not begin in play
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control (Y/N)&lt;/strong&gt;: Standard&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: Standard&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4th Tiebreaker&lt;/strong&gt;: If a list contains two or more multiple-model solos, all casualties are counted toward the same solo until it is completely destroyed.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
		</content>	
	</page>
	<page>
		<title>SR 2012 Appendix</title>
		<anchor>appendix</anchor>
		<content>
			&lt;h2&gt;Official WARMACHINE &amp;HORDES Tournament Variants&lt;/h2&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Steamroller 2012 (SR2012) provides an official format for Tournament Organizers (TOs) of WARMACHINE and HORDES events. We realize that not all communities are the same, so we have compiled this appendix to provide official variants to specific areas of the SR2012 document.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					These variants can be used to alter a single rule, or they can be combined to form a more casual or competitive format based on the preferences of the players, the needs of the venue, or event time constraints. No matter what choices you make, any combination of variants from this document will constitute an official SR2012 tournament format.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Variant rules are available for the following sections of the SR2012 rules:
						&lt;ol&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#army&quot;&gt;Army Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#painting&quot;&gt;Painting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rounds&quot;&gt;Number of Rounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#timing&quot;&gt;Game Timing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#scenarios&quot;&gt;Scenario Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#victory&quot;&gt;Victory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#standings&quot;&gt;Final Standings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Using Variants&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						This document will revisit several rules areas of the SR2012 document. A review of the baseline version of a rule will be listed followed by variant keyword(s) and the description of the variant(s). Not all sections of the SR2012 rules document have variant options. For example, players must always practice good sportsmanship, so no variants are available for playing outside the sportsmanship parameters set forth in the baseline SR2012 rules. 
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						SR2012 appendix variants make it easy for an EO to tailor events to the needs of his/her player community. By using the appropriate variant keywords, players can reference this document for details, which will help keep pre-tournament announcements concise.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;army&quot;&gt;1. Army List Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Second list optional. All lists are subject to the same point constraints and must be led by warcasters/warlocks from the same faction. Players cannot include the same version of a model or unit with FA: C in more than one list.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;X List(s) Required&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Players must bring exactly X army lists and must play each army list at least once during the event.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Characters Restricted&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Different versions of the same character model/unit cannot be included in more than one of a player’s lists. (Example: A player cannot include Alexia, Mistress of the Witchfire in one list and Alexia Ciannor &amp;the Risen in another.)
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Modern Warfare&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Players can include only the most recent incarnation of a given character model/unit in any of their army lists. (Example: A player can include Alexia, Mistress of the Witchfire in one of his army lists but cannot use Alexia Ciannor &amp;the Risen at this event.)
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Unrestricted Characters&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Models/units with FA: C can be included in more than one list.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Theme Forces: Tier X Required&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Players must use a Theme Force of Tier X or higher in all lists. Models/units with FA: C can be included in more than one list (if included in more than one Theme Force).
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Divide and Conquer&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The EO will announce the expected number of rounds to be played at the beginning of the tournament. Divide the number of rounds to be played by the required number of lists for each player. The result (rounded down) is the number of times each list must be played during the tournament. Divide and Conquer events must use the X Lists Required variant.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Example: If a tournament requires that each player brings two army lists and has five rounds, then each player would have to play each list at least twice (4 divided by 2). In this variant a player must inform his opponent if he has no choice of which warcaster or warlock he must play prior to a game. If a player receives a bye he must choose a list to use for the bye round.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;painting&quot;&gt;2. Painting Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Painted armies are not required.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Basic Painting Required&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							All models must be primed and basecoated. Players must present the intended final color scheme on all parts of the model. Bases can be unfinished. Hardcore Painting Required – For Hardcore tournaments, all the Steamroller ?Modeling and Painting? and ?Conversions? rules apply. In addition, all models must be completely painted. This means that every model must be painted with a reasonable diversity of color. Individual elements of the miniature must be distinguishable by color or shading. For instance, flesh must be a different color than hair or clothing; metal should be a different color than leather. The base is part of the model, so don't neglect it! Bases must be finished with sand or flock or otherwise modeled and painted.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Models that do not meet these requirements will not be eligible for play. Whether a model is completed is the decision of the event organizer. As a general rule, if someone feels the need to justify why a model is completed, it probably isn’t. In order to be eligible for any prizes that are awarded based on quality and technique the owning player must paint all presented models themselves.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;rounds&quot;&gt;3. Number of Rounds Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							All players participate in every round. Play a number of rounds required to determine a clear winner.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;X-Round Event&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							This tournament will have no more than X rounds regardless of the number of players. This type of event can end before X rounds if there is one player with more tournament points than any other player at the end of a round.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The X-Round Event variant can be paired with a Final Standings variant when the number of rounds is reduced below the number of rounds recommended in the SR2012 core rules.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;timing&quot;&gt;4. Game Timing Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Basic round times are randomly decreased or increased by a variable (d3 × extension length) that is not revealed to players. During each game, one turn extension is allowed for each player. Dice down is called when round time is complete.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No Time Limits&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Games are untimed. A round continues until all players have completed their games.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Relaxed Time Limits&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Use the baseline round, turn, and extension length of an event two sizes higher.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Casual Time Limits&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Use the baseline round, turn, and extension length of the event with the nexthigher point size.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Hardcore Time Limits&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Use the baseline round, turn, and extension length of the event with the nextlower point size.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Frenzy Time Limits&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Use the baseline round, turn, and extension length of an event two sizes lower.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No Extensions&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The allowance of one turn extension per game is removed.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Chess Clocks&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Instead of timing each turn, chess clocks will be used. Baseline round times with no variable are used, but the chess clock replaces the turn length. Each player’s clock will be set based on the following equation:
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Base round time × 0.53 = Player clock total (rounded up to the nearest minute)
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							When a player moves a model, rolls dice, or takes significant time to make decisions during the other player’s turn, the player whose turn it is has the option of switching to the opponent’s time on the chess clock while these actions are resolved.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							When chess clocks are used, a player must take meaningful turns, fully activating all his models, or risk disqualification. If a player’s clock runs out of time, that player loses the game.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Death Clock&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Use the Chess Clocks variant. Additionally, dice down will not be called in any round.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;scenarios&quot;&gt;5. Scenario Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							For each round, the EO selects a scenario that all players will play. The EO keeps scenarios secret until the start of each round of games.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Scenario(s) (X)&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The listed scenarios or scenario groups that will be played at the event are revealed to all players prior to the event. This information might also include the order in which the scenarios will be played.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No Kill Box&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The Kill Box artifice will be removed from all scenarios played at the event.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No Reinforcements&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The Reinforcements artifice will be removed from all scenarios played at the event.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Non-Interactive Objectives&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Scenarios with objectives will not be played at the event or objectives lose all abilities except for &quot;Objective.&quot; The &quot;Guidons&quot; scenario cannot be played when this variant is used. Objectives are considered friendly models to all other models.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Warcaster/Warlock Reinforcements&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Add a warcaster or warlock to the reinforcements section of your army list(s). Warjack/warbeast points for the warcaster/warlock are added to the reinforcements total. Reinforcement warcasters/warlocks are granted 5 additional warjack/warbeast points. The army is still counted as having a standard FA for the base point size of the game.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							If a player is using a Theme Force, the second warcaster or warlock must be chosen from the same faction. Mercenary players must choose from a contract that allows the primary warcaster(s). Minion players must choose from a pact that allows the primary warlock(s). All other reinforcement modelsfollow the baseline reinforcement rules for Theme Forces.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Artifice(s) (X)&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The listed artifices will be added to all eligible scenarios played at the event. Reinforcements cannot be added to radial scenarios; use the reinforcements line diagram below to add a reinforcements line to any non-radial scenario.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt; src=&quot;images/variants-Reinforcements.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Warcaster/Warlock Reinforcements&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; />
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;victory&quot;&gt;6. Victory Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							Assassination Victory, Scenario Victory, Control Points Tiebreaker, Army Points Remaining Tiebreaker, Army Points Destroyed Tiebreaker.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No ’Caster Kill &lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							This event does not use ’Caster Kill as a scenario win condition. When a warcaster or warlock is destroyed, the game continues until a scenario victory is achieved or one player has no models remaining.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;No Tiebreakers&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							This event will not use tiebreakers. If time expires the game is a tie.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;standings&quot;&gt;7. Final Standings Variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							If there is no clear winner at the end of the tournament, use the Strength of Schedule tiebreaker followed by Control Points and then Army Points Destroyed.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Large Event Scoring&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							In larger events, players dropping out of the tournament adversely affect their opponents’ strength of schedule. If there is no clear winner at the end of an event using large event scoring, count the tournament points scored divided by the number of games played by each opponent of the tied players. For an opponent who did not score any tournament points, use a value equal to 1 divided by the total number of rounds in the event.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							For example, after four rounds Jason and Doug are tied for second place. To break the tie, the EO adds up the tournament points and divides by the number of games played by Jason's opponents during the previous four rounds. The EO does the same for Doug's opponents and compares the total to break the tie.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The player whose opponents have the highest total score has the best strength of schedule score and earns the higher rank. If strength of schedule is the same for both players, go to Control Points and then Army Points as normal.
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Control Point Scoring&lt;/h4&gt;
						If there is no clear winner at the end of a tournament, use the Control Points tiebreaker followed by Army Points Destroyed and then Strength of Schedule.	
					&lt;h4&gt;Assassin Scoring&lt;/h4&gt;
						If there is no clear winner at the end of a tournament, use the number of ’caster kill wins as the tiebreak condition (followed by Army Points Destroyed and then Control Points, if needed).
					&lt;h4&gt;Destruction Scoring&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							If there is no clear winner at the end of a tournament, use the total number of enemy army points destroyed or removed from play during the tournament as the tiebreak condition (followed by Control Points and then Strength of Schedule, if needed). The method below should also be used to determine awards based on army point destruction. Points are scored each time a model/unit is destroyed/removed from play (For example, For example, if Thagrosh, Prophet of Everblight returned a Scythean to play using Dark Revival, the opponent earns 9 points for each time he destroyed the warbeast).
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							When counting destroyed army points each round use the following methods:
							&lt;ul&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Destroyed models/units are worth their army point value.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Units below 50% of their starting number (rounding up) are worth 50% of their army points (rounding up) including all attachments.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Warcasters and warlocks are worth 5 army points each. Non-warcaster/warlock models included with warcasters and warlocks have no additional value.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Inert warjacks and wild warbeasts are worth their full army point values.&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ul&gt;
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							When calculating model value, use the values printed on the model/unit¡¦s card even if that model/unit was brought into the army via other means (such as Dark Industries) or if the models received a discount during army-building (such as the Call of the Wild Tier 4 Theme Force benefit).
						&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Finals Tables&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							When creating match-ups for the final round of an event, the TO pairs the current top four players on two &quot;finals tables&quot; The first finals table matches the current first-ranked player against the current second-ranked player. The second finals table matches the current third-ranked player against the current fourth-ranked player. 
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The winner of the first finals table wins the event, and his opponent wins second place. The winner of the second finals table wins third place. Standings beyond third place should be calculated using Strength of Schedule followed by Control Points in the case of a tie.
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							The Finals Tables variant should be used only in events that are planned for the number of rounds recommended in the Steamroller 2012 rules based on player attendance, and it cannot be combined with any other Final Standings variant. Also, this is not a preferred variant, as it places the luck of the draw (as to when someone lost to the champion) above game-related scoring metrics such as opponent difficulty, control points, army points, and assassination.
						&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						TOs should always consider the best way to run events for their players given the resources they have available. These resources include a place to run the event, the amount of time available, tokens to mark the corners or center of scenario zones, timers, and so on. For example, if you have limited time per day at the venue, you might want to consider running a larger event over two days.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						Use the variants provided in this appendix to run an event that best fits the resources you have available as well as the preferred play style of your players.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Sample Combinations&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Hardcore&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;ul&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;One List Required&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Painting Required&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Time Limits (Death Clock timing variant allowed)&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Scenario: Close Quarters&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Artifice: Kill Box&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Assassin Scoring&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Limited Venue Hours&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;ul&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;3-Round Event&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Control Point Scoring&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Casual Tournament&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;ul&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Scenario Scoring&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;No Time Limits&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;No ’Caster Kill&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						By varying the SR2012 Appendix rules in use, the standard Steamroller format offers a diversity of formats to create a unique combination of tournaments at a convention or weekend event. See below for an example of a three-day event. Please take note of the thematic names attached to each event; these small touches can be used to inspire players’ lists, generate unique prize ideas, and build excitement.
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Friday: 50-pt SR2012 &quot;Last Rites&quot; Tournament&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							SR2012 Appendix rules:
						&lt;/p&gt;
							&lt;ul&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Artifice: Kill Box&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Saturday: 75-pt SR2012 &quot;Hardcore!&quot; Tournament&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							SR2012 Appendix rules:
						&lt;/p&gt;
						&lt;ul&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;One List Required&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Painting Required&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Time Limits&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Scenario: Close Quarters&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Artifice: Kill Box&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;li&gt;Assassin Scoring&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;h4&gt;Sunday: 35-pt SR2012 &quot;Dual Strike&quot; Tournament&lt;/h4&gt;
						&lt;p&gt;
							SR2012 Appendix rules:
						&lt;/p&gt;
							&lt;ul&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Artifice: Reinforcements&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Warcaster/Warlock Reinforcements&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h2&gt;Privateer Press Tournament Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					WARMACHINE and HORDES Masters and Hardcore tournaments are held to a higher standard than other Steamroller tournaments, and certain requirements must be met in order to host one at a convention or event. First and foremost, all Masters and Hardcore tournaments must be pre-approved by Privateer Press. All the requirements below must be met in order to qualify for an officially sanctioned Masters or Hardcore tournament, and only approved tournaments will receive Masters trophies or Hardcore medals for prize support.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Masters Tournaments - U.S. Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Convention attendee minimum: 1,000+ or 100+ WARMACHINE/HORDES players&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Masters tournament participant minimum: 32+*&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Qualifiers: Any qualifiers must be held at the same convention, but are not required.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Format: 35 or 50 or 75 Point Steamroller&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;3 Lists Required&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Chess Clock or Death Clock timing variants are allowed&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Prize Support: Steamroller trophies ($74.99) or Masters trophy ($100.00) (must be purchased from Privateer Press)&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						If your Masters tournament contains qualifiers, the total number of players in the qualifiers must be a minimum of 32 distinct players. For instance, it is acceptable to have two Masters tournament qualifiers with 16+ distinct players and a final Masters tournament of 8 distinct players seeded from the two qualifier tournaments.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Masters Tournaments - International Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Convention attendee minimum: 500+ or 50+ WARMACHINE/HORDES players&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Masters tournament participant minimum: 32+ *&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Qualifiers: Any qualifiers must be held at the same convention, but are not required.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Format: 35 or 50 75 Point Steamroller&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;3 Lists Required&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Chess Clock or Death Clock timing variants allowed&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Prize Support: Steamroller ($74.99) or Masters trophy ($100.00) purchased from Privateer Press&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;
						* If your Masters tournament contains qualifiers, the total number of players in the qualifiers must be a minimum of 32 distinct players. For instance, it is acceptable to have two Masters tournament qualifiers with 16+ distinct players and a final Masters tournament of 8 distinct players seeded from the two qualifier tournaments.
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;h3&gt;Hardcore Tournaments - U.S. &amp;International Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Convention attendee minimum: 100+&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Hardcore tournament participant minimum: 32+&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Qualifiers: No qualifiers are allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Format: 35 or 50 Point Steamroller&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;1 List Required&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Painting Required&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Hardcore Time Limits (Death Clock timing variant allowed)&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Scenario: Close Quarters&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Artifice: Kill Box&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Assassination Scoring&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Prize Support: Hardcore medals ($50.00) (must be purchased from Privateer Press)&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
			Download the sample &lt;a href=&quot;pdfs/Steamroller-2012-player-record-sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Steamroller 2012 Player Record Sheet&lt;/a&gt;
		</content>	
	</page>
	<page>
		<title>SR 2012 Information</title>
		<anchor>information</anchor>
		<content>
			&lt;p&gt;
			In Steamroller tournaments, players face off in a series of games and pit their skills against a gauntlet of opponents to determine who will emerge victorious. Steamroller is ideal for groups of 8 to 64 players and promotes fast and furious play while stressing the ability to adapt to a variety of scenarios.
		&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;Player Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players participating in a Steamroller 2012 (SR2012) event must bring all their own models, stat cards, dice, measuring devices, markers, and templates they require for play. Tokens representing in-game effects such as focus, fury, spells, and abilities are required and must be kept adjacent to the corresponding model on the table. Players should also bring a copy of the SR2012 scenario reference sheet for use during the tournament.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Army Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players must bring two legible copies of all their army lists complete with point costs. Army list point totals cannot exceed the point size chosen for the game and cannot fall more than 2 points under the point size chosen for the event. Players must incorporate all bonus warjack or warbeast points in their army list(s) point total. A 50-point Kaelyssa army, for example, must include 55 to 57 points of models.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players can bring a second list if they choose. All lists must be led by warcasters/warlocks from the same faction. Mercenary players can use different contracts or Theme Forces for their lists. Minion players can use different pacts or Theme Forces for their lists. Players cannot include the same version of a model or unit with FA:C in more than one list. The original and epic incarnation(s) of a character do not count as the same version of a model. Any player-determined model relationships (attached, client, marshaled, etc.) must be specified in the list and cannot change between rounds.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				SR2012 contains scenarios that use reinforcements. Reinforcements are additional models added to a player’s army list(s) only for scenarios that have the reinforcements artifice. These models and their points must be shown on a player’s army list(s) in case a reinforcements scenario is played. Detailed rules for reinforcements are found in the Artifices section (p. 9)
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				SR2012 allows all released Theme Forces to be used. Anyone using a Theme Force must have the Theme Force available for the event organizer’s reference (in order to verify the army list) and for the opponent’s reference (in order to view the Theme Force’s special rules). Permission is hereby granted to photocopy the Theme Forces section from the WARMACHINE and HORDES expansion books as well as any Theme Forces appearing in No Quarter Magazine for personal, non-commercial use only and subject to the terms found within those original source materials.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Modeling and Painting&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				All models used in Privateer Press organized play events must be Privateer Press miniatures from the WARMACHINE or HORDES ranges. The miniatures must be fully assembled on the appropriately sized base for which the model was designed. Any non–Privateer Press models, unassembled miniatures, or inappropriately based models are not permitted.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Models that have not yet been released to the general public at the time of the event are not permitted unless those models are readily available at the event venue (such as convention-release models in tournaments at that convention). The Extreme versions of models are perfectly acceptable for use in organized play.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Privateer Press encourages players to have a fully painted force on the table. Games with painted armies are more interesting to watch and generally enhance the experience for all. Although painting is not required, players should take this chance to show off all aspects of the hobby. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Model Conversions&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Playing with a uniquely individualized and painted force is one of the most rewarding aspects of the hobby.Just as with information disclosure and sportsmanship, players are expected to be unambiguous about model representation. The following rules must be adhered to when using converted models in organized play.  These rules are meant not to limit a player’s modeling options but rather to allow creativity without generating an environment that could become confusing during game play. At his discretion, an event organizer can make exceptions to these rules to approve any reasonable conversion.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;
				A converted model must contain a majority of parts from the WARMACHINE or HORDES model for which the rules were written. For example, a Testament of Menoth conversion must be composed mostly of parts from the Testament of Menoth model. The end result of any conversion must be clearly identifiable as the intended miniature and accurately represent its weapons and equipment as listed in its rules. Any conversions must beclearly pointed out to your opponent before the game to avoid confusion.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;
				On warrior models, converting and swapping weapons is acceptable provided the new weapon represents the same type of weapon replaced (like swapping one sword for another). Anything relating to a weapon’s	specific rules must be maintained to avoid confusion on the tabletop. For example, a weapon with Chain Weapon must still be modeled as a chain-style weapon, and a weapon’s length must be considered when converting weapons with Reach.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;
				Weapons cannot be swapped on warjack and warbeast models. Since many of the ’jacks and beasts utilize the same chassis or torso, the weapons are the most identifiable part of the model when looking across the tabletop. Converting warjacks and warbeasts is still encouraged, but the aesthetics of the weapons must be maintained. Modifying weapons is permitted, as long as the end result is easily identifiable as the intended warjack or warbeast’s proper weapon.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;
				The models with &quot;upgrade kit&quot; blisters are an exception to the standard conversion rules. Because the parts in these blisters define an entirely separate model for rules purposes, all parts must be clearly visible on the model for legal tournament use. For example, a helljack with one claw and one harpoon is not Malice. The model must have the correct head, harpoon blade, and all three spirit parts from the Malice upgrade kit inorder to be considered Malice.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;
				Miniatures must be on their appropriately-sized WARMACHINE/HORDES base, but scenic details can be added. The base’s perimeter must always be considered when modeling scenic details. While it is acceptable for scenic elements to overhang the base’s edge, the base itself and not the scenic elements is used for all measurements. The edge of a model’s base must not obscured to the point that accurate measuring becomes difficult or impossible.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Sportsmanship&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				A fair and honest in-game environment is required in order for everyone to have fun. Players must accurately execute the rules of the game and fully cooperate with opponents to honestly answer any questions that arise before and during the game. Players are also responsible for holding their opponents to the same standards.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The event organizer will not be able to observe every game. If your opponent is doing something that is making you uncomfortable—stalling, bending the rules, or outright cheating—tell your opponent about it. Explain what he can do to remedy the situation in order to maintain a fair, honest, and fun in-game environment. If the behavior continues or a dispute arises, call the EO and explain the situation. The EO always has the final word on rules questions or debates. Players must accept all rulings made by the EO whether or not they agree.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players must present a mature and polite demeanor to their opponents and the EO. Failure to do so will result in immediate disqualification. An EO can also disqualify a player for any incident that is deemed unsporting. This includes, but is not limited to, offensive or abusive conduct, bullying, cheating, constant rules arguments, improper play, stalling, and other inappropriate actions. Disqualified players are not eligible for any awards or prizes and are barred from further participation in the event and any other related events.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Occasionally circumstances will prompt a player to concede a game during a tournament. Concessions are not recommended since there is almost always a chance for victory. In the case of a concession, the winning player will be awarded a win, half the control points (rounding up) for a scenario win and army points destroyed based on an assassination using current board conditions. The player who conceded will receive a loss and no points in any category. An EO can disqualify a player from a tournament if a concession is deemed unsportsmanlike.
			&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;Event Organizer Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				When estimating the overall length of a tournament, an EO should add extra time for each round to cover the variable, allow time to do pairings, get people to their new tables, and get the next round started.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Number of Rounds&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The event will run until one player has more tournament points than any other player at the end of a round. Once this condition is met, the event ends without additional games.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players participate in a timed format with all players participating in every round. The number of players participating in the tournament determines the maximum number of games usually required to determine a winner.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Players&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Rounds&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;8 or fewer&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3-round event&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;9 to 16&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;4-round event&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;17 to 32&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5-round event&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;33 to 64&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6-round event&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;65 to 128&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;7-round event&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;First Round Pairings&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Shuffle all the tournament record sheets together. Take the top two sheets and set them to one side. This gives you the first pairing. Without shuffling the pile again, remove the next two sheets and repeat the process until all players have an opponent. If you have an odd number of players, see ?Byes &amp;Odd Number of Players? below.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Once you have completed the pairings, note the opposing player’s ID on each player’s sheet to track that player’s opponents. Record the tournament point and control point scores for each player when the round ends. Ignore the subtotal boxes for now; they only matter for rounds after the first.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Subsequent Pairings&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				From here on, all pairings and ranks are based on tournament point subtotals and pairings from previous rounds. After all games in the previous round have been completed, sort the tournament record sheets into piles based on the number of tournament points. Shuffle each pile.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Take the top sheet of the pile with the greatest number of tournament points and choose the first opponent in the pile he has not already played. Set this pair aside and repeat the process. When you reach the end of a pile move to the next pile. If a pile has an odd number of players, pair the last player against someone from the next-highest tournament point pile. Do not do this with any individual player more than once per event. Again, once you have all the pairings, write the opposing player’s name in the appropriate column on each player’s sheet. It might take several attempts to find pairings that avoid duplicating match-ups.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Some EOs use additional criteria for their pairings. Keep in mind that any additional criteria must come after matching players with the same number of tournament points who have not already played one another.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Byes &amp;Odd Number of Players&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Steamroller games take place between two players. In the case of an odd number of players, one player will receive a bye. A player receiving a bye sits out of the current round and receives 1 tournament point, half the control points (rounded up) for a scenario win, and half the army point level (rounded up) for the event.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The EO will randomly determine which player receives the bye if a tournament begins with an odd number of players. In subsequent rounds, the EO will randomly select a player from those with the lowest tournament point totals. The EO should ensure that the same player does not receive a bye more than once per event.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Game Timing&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Event Point Size&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base Round Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Turn Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Extension Length (minutes)&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;70&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Each round in a Steamroller event has a variable round length. Before each round begins, the EO rolls a d3 and multiplies the result by the variable, the turn extension length for the event size. He then rolls a d6 to determine whether the variable will be subtracted from (on a result of 1–3) or added to (on a result of 4–6) the base round length (shown above) to determine the overall round length.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				During rounds that use scenarios with the reinforcements artifice, the EO will add two extensions to the overall round length after the variable is subtracted or added. In this case do not exceed the maximum round length of base round length plus three extensions. The EO will not announce the result of this roll or reveal the amount of time remaining in a game to players.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Adjustments to Rounds Using Reinforcements	&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Event Point Size&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Reinforcements &lt;br&gt; (Points)&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Player Timing &lt;br&gt; (Per Player)&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;NA&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Variable Roll&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Overall Round Length&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;-3&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base -1 Extension&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base +1 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+1&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+2&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;+3&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Base +3 Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				After the time for a round has expired, the EO calls ?dice down.? If a player is in the process of moving a model, he finishes that movement, then the turn and game end. If the player is in the process of making a roll of any kind, he completes that single roll, then the turn and game end. If the roll is an attack roll that directly hits its target, resolve the direct hit damage roll as well.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				At dice down, resolve all end-of-turn effects that would occur including the removal of models if applicable. Models that have not entered play yet or were removed from the table do not enter play and do not count as destroyed.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Dice down or assassination prompts a final iteration of scenario scoring even though the game is over. Assassination victories always take priority over a scenario win.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				If a game does not have a clear winner after dice down, check the scenario for how to determine the winner. Before the tournament begins the EO should instruct all players how the tiebreaker system works, as described in the SR2012 scenario reference sheet.			
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Turn Timing&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Steamroller also uses a timed turn length to ensure a fair play environment. Players in each game use a timer to track the fixed amount of time available for each turn. This time limit is based on the point size of the event. A player’s timer begins after the resolution of continuous effects.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				If a player is executing a model/unit’s normal movement when his turn time expires, he finishes moving that model/unit, then his turn ends. If the player is in the process of making a roll of any kind after movement is complete, he completes that single roll, then his turn ends. If the roll is an attack roll that directly hits its target, resolve the direct hit damage roll as well.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				When a player moves a model, rolls dice, or takes significant time to make decisions during the other player’s turn, the player whose turn it is has the option of stopping the clock while these actions are resolved.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Turn Extension&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Once per game, each player can extend his turn length with an extension. A player can extend his turn length by declaring he is doing so during his turn. After the current turn time expires, the active player’s opponent resets the clock for the turn extension, then the active player continues his turn. Extensions cannot extend a turn past the total round time.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				During rounds that use scenarios with the reinforcements artifice, each player is granted a second extension. The second extension is the same duration as a normal extension and cannot be combined with another extension on the same turn.
			&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;Scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Scenario Selection&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;				
				Steamroller 2012 contains six groups of scenarios. The scenarios in each group have similar objectives. In order to ensure that tournaments contain a variety of different scenario types, EOs must select a scenario from each group before they can choose from the same group again.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Round&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Group Choices Available&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Group Chosen&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2, 3, 4, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2, 3, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2, 5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5, 6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The EO should choose scenarios before a tournament to ensure they have the required materials for those scenarios. The selected scenarios can be played in any order. The random scenario table below can also be used.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Scenarios cannot be repeated in a standard tournament. All players play the same scenario each round. The EO keeps the upcoming scenario secret until the start of each round of games.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				During each round the EO should provide at least one copy of the scenario being played for every four players (every two tables) in the event. After declaring the scenario, the EO will read the rules for that scenario aloud. The EO should answer questions concerning the scenario before the round begins. Players are responsible for making sure they understand the scenario.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				EOs should stress that it is imperative all players pursue both the scenario and assassination victory conditions during the game as players do not know when the round time is going to expire.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;table class=&quot;tinyTable&quot;&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;D6 Roll: Group\D3 Roll: Scenario&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;1 - Center&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Close Quarters&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Gauntlet&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Overrun&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;2 - Distant&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Guidons&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Supply and Demand&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Destruction&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;3 - Dual&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Incursion&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Process of Elimination&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Outflank, Outfight, Outlast&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;4 - Flank&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;A Flag Too Far&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Bunkers&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Envelopment&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;5 - Objective&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Demolition&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Incoming&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Restoration&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;6 - Radial&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Command and Control&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Diversion&lt;/td&gt;
					&lt;td&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				SR2012 adds flank scenarios that use flank deployment as illustrated in the diagram below. Distances that are measured from a player’s board edge or back of deployment zone can use a point on the board edge as indicated here.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt; src=&quot;images/deployment-flank.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flank Deployment Scenario&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; />
			&lt;p&gt;
				SR2012 also contains radial scenarios. Mechanics that are measured from a player’s board edge or back of deployment zone can use a point on either of the two board edges indicated below
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt; src=&quot;images/deployment-radial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flank Deployment Scenario&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; />
			&lt;p&gt;
				In order to mitigate the initiative advantage of the first player, the deployment zones in SR2012 are different sizes based on turn order.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				In standard and flank deployment, the first player has a 7&quot; deployment zone (13&quot; AD) and the second player has a 10&quot; deployment zone (16&quot; AD). Theme Force bonuses do not alter the width of flank deployment zones.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				In radial deployment, the first player has a 17&quot; deployment zone (23&quot; AD) and the second player has a 20&quot; deployment zone (26&quot; AD).
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Terrain&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Terrain is a key element for games of WARMACHINE and HORDES. Terrain pieces should present choices to both players but should not give an undue advantage to either. To reinforce this principle, terrain should be relatively symmetrical on a table. For example, if one side of the board contains a forest, a hill, and a linear obstacle then the other side should contain terrain that provides concealment, elevation, and cover as well.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				As a general rule, an average table should contain five to seven pieces of terrain placed close enough to eliminate large open areas without unduly constricting movement. The size of terrain pieces is also important.  No piece should be insignificantly small or extremely large; terrain pieces that range from 4? to 8? in length and width are best.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The type, number, and placement of terrain pieces are up to the EO, but the following guidelines must be followed when setting up tables:
					&lt;ul&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Do not place terrain within deployment zone areas. This does not apply to Advance Deployment areas.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;All terrain pieces must be placed at least 3? away from other terrain pieces. This includes terrain pieces granted by Theme Force bonuses.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Do not place impassable terrain within zones when playing scenarios that use them. Note that all other terrain types can be placed within the zones.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				EOs can choose whether to fully represent the zones presented in the scenario packet with templates or mark the corners of rectangular zones or the center point of circular zones. If center or corner markers are used, players can measure the zone whenever it is relevant to fulfilling scenario conditions. Any attempted abuse of this rule is grounds for disqualification. If a scenario zone marker is inadvertently moved during play, pause the clock and reset the zone marker’s position. If scenario scoring occurred while a marker was in an incorrect position the control points stand, even if this error is noticed after the fact.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Artifices&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				SR2012 introduces artifices to scenario play. Artifices are mandatory additional rules present in certain scenarios.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h4&gt;Kill Box&lt;/h4&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Starting on the first player’s second turn, if a player ends his turn with a friendly warcaster/warlock within 10? of any board edge, that warcaster/warlock is destroyed.
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h4&gt;Reinforcements&lt;/h4&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Reinforcements are additional models, up to a specified point value (see p. 29), added to a player’s army list(s) that are used only in scenarios with the reinforcements artifice. These models are separate from the main part of each list and must be included, with battlegroup/marshal affiliation if applicable, even though reinforcements scenarios might not be played. Reinforcements follow the normal Field Allowance rules for their corresponding list. Players can field reinforcements without using all of the reinforcement points available. Reinforcements must follow the restrictions of any Theme Force to which they are added and benefit from any applicable bonuses (including Field Allowance) but are not counted toward satisfying tier requirements.
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Warcasters, Warlocks, models/units with the Pre-Deployment or Attached rule, and models/unit that cannot begin the game in play cannot be reinforcements. Reinforcement models cannot be bonded. Reinforcements lose the Ambush ability. Reinforcements with the Prey ability choose their Prey target after both players are deployed. During the maintenance phase, on a player’s second turn or later, these models can be placed within 3? of any point on the reinforcements line shown in the scenario diagram. All of a player’s reinforcements must be placed on the same turn.				
				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Adjustments to Rounds Using Reinforcements
				&lt;/p&gt;

			&lt;h4&gt;3. Interactive Objectives&lt;/h4&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;
					Replace the basic objective properties listed in the scenario reference sheet with the objective card type (p. xx) indicated in the scenario.
				&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Starting the Game&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players can ask to see their opponent’s lists at any time, including before list selection, before the start of the game, and during play. A player must take care not to disrupt the flow of the game while doing this. All models in each list must be presented to an opponent upon request before list selection.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				After the pairings and scenarios for the game have been announced but before the starting roll, each player secretly chooses one of his lists and conceals the card for the selected warcaster or warlock on the table. A player cannot change lists after making this selection. Both players reveal their lists simultaneously.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Both players roll a d6 for the starting roll. The player with the higher result can choose to be the first or second player. The second player chooses his table edge. The first player deploys first and takes the first turn. The EO has the option to predetermine table sides for players in order to save time during deployment.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Final Standings&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Players score tournament points based on the outcome of each game. A player gains 1 tournament point for a win and 0 for a loss or draw. Tournament points determine a player’s current standing in a tournament.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				In the case of two players with the same number of tournament points, determine which one ranks higher by calculating strength of schedule.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				Count the tournament points scored by each opponent of the tied players to determine strength of schedule.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
				The player whose opponents have the highest total score has the best strength of schedule score and earns the higher rank. If strength of schedule is the same for both players, the player who accrued the most control points throughout the tournament earns the higher rank. If control points are also the same for both players, the player who accrued the most enemy army points destroyed throughout the tournament earns the higher rank. When counting destroyed army points, use the destruction scoring rules found on p. 36.
			&lt;/p&gt;
		</content>
	</page>
	<page>
		<title>SR 2012 Objectives</title>
		<anchor>objectives</anchor>
		<content>
			&lt;h2&gt;Steamroller Objective Cards&lt;/h2&gt;			
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;Guidon&quot;>Guidon Bearer Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt; This model cannot activate during the first round of the game and cannot activate unless it is controlled by  a warcaster/warlock. This model activates during its controlling  warcaster/warlock’s army’s turn.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock  is within 4&quot;of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot  be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and  cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be placed, pushed,  slammed, or thrown) except during activation.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Raise the Guidon –  Once per turn during this model’s activation, it  can be placed B2B with its controlling warcaster/warlock.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Rallying Point – While this model is controlled by a warcaster/warlock, models/units in the controlling warcaster/warlock’s army that are within 4&quot;of this model gain Fearless  &lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-fearless.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Fearless Symbol&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;FuelCache&quot;>Fuel Cache Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;	
					&lt;li&gt;Flammable – When this model is destroyed, models within 2&quot;suffer a POW 14 magical damage roll.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Fuel – While this model is controlled by a warcaster/warlock, models/units in the controlling warcaster/warlock’s army beginning their activations within 4? of this model can run, charge, or make power attacks without being forced or spending focus that  activation.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Manual Activation – This model cannot activate during the first round of the game and cannot activate unless it is controlled by a warcaster/warlock. This model activates during its controlling warcaster/warlock’s army’s turn.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4? of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be  placed, pushed, slammed, or thrown) except during activation..&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Resupply – At the start of this model’s activation, remove 3 points of damage from it.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;Monolith&quot;>Monolith Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;	
					&lt;li&gt;Field Reinforcement – At the start of this model’s activation, you can remove one power token from it or add one power token to it, up to a maximum of three. This model gains +1 ARM for each power token currently on it.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Manual Activation – This model cannot activate during the first round of the game and cannot activate unless it is controlled by a warcaster/warlock. This model activates during its controlling warcaster/warlock’s army’s turn.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4&quot;of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be placed, pushed, slammed, or thrown) except during activation.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;ExplosivesCache&quot;>Explosives Cache Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;	
					&lt;li&gt;Explosive Charge – One per turn during its activation, this model can place a 5&quot;AOE within 4&quot;of its controlling warcaster/warlock. Models within the AOE suffer an unboostable POW 14 magical damage roll and are knocked down.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Flammable – When this model is destroyed, models within 2&quot;suffer a POW 14 magical damage roll.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Manual Activation –  This model cannot activate during the first round of the game and cannot activate unless it is controlled by a warcaster/warlock. This model activates during its controlling warcaster/warlock’s army’s turn.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4&quot;of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be placed, pushed, slammed, or thrown) except during activation.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;ArtilleryEmplacement&quot;>Artillery Emplacement Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;	
					&lt;li&gt;Flammable – When this model is destroyed, models within 2&quot;suffer a POW 14 magical damage roll.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Incoming! – During this model’s activation, you can choose an intended point of impact within a zone. Using this model as the point of origin, a 3&quot;AOE deviates from the intended point of impact. Models within the AOE are hit and suffer an unboostable POW 12 magical damage roll. The AOE is rough terrain and remains in play for one round.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Manual Activation –  This model cannot activate during the first round of the game and cannot activate unless it is controlled by a warcaster/warlock. This model activates during its controlling warcaster/warlock’s army’s turn.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4&quot;of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be placed, pushed, slammed, or thrown) except during activation.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/symbol-construct.jpg&quot;alt=&quot;Objectives have the construct atribute&quot;class=&quot;symbol&quot; /&lt;&lt;a name=&quot;RestorationCache&quot;>Restoration Cache Steamroller Objective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;ARM: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Damage: 20&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Manual Activation – At the start of this model’s activation, remove d3 points of damage from it, remove d3 points of damage from other friendly models within 4&quot;of it, and remove continuous effects from other friendly models within 4&quot;of it.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Objective – A player controls an objective if his warcaster/warlock is within 4&quot;of it and no enemy models contest it. Objectives cannot be targeted or damaged during the first turn of the game and cannot be moved (cannot advance, and cannot be placed, pushed, slammed, or thrown) except during activation.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;Restoration – At the start of this model’s activation, remove d3 points of damage from it, remove d3 points of damage from other friendly models within 4½ of it, and remove continuous effects from other friendly models within 4½ of it.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
		</content>
	</page>
</pages>
