<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<terms>
<term>    <anchor>1st_tiebreaker</anchor>    <name>1st Tiebreaker</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; If time runs out before a player has won the game, the player who owns the most warcasters/warlocks remaining in play wins the game. If both players own the same number of warcasters/warlocks in play, check the 2nd tiebreaker to determine the winner.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>2nd_tiebreaker</anchor>    <name>2nd Tiebreaker</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; The player who has the most control points wins the game. If both players have the same number of control points, check the 3rd tiebreaker to determine the winner.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>3rd_tiebreaker</anchor>    <name>3rd Tiebreaker</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Tally the point cost of the remaining models/units owned by each player. Double the value of nonwarcaster/warlock models/units (rounded up) within the area(s) designated by the scenario. Ignore models without a PC, inert warjacks, wild warbeasts, and fleeing models when checking 3rd tiebreaker conditions. The player with more army points worth of models remaining wins the game.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>4th_tiebreaker</anchor>    <name>4th Tiebreaker</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Tally each player’s army points that have been destroyed or removed from play as described below. The player whose opponent suffered more army points destroyed/removed from play wins the game. If both players have destroyed the same number of army points the game is a tie.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; Models/units are worth their army point value.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Units below 50% of their starting number (rounding up) are worth 50% of their army points (rounding up) including all attachments.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Inert warjacks and wild warbeasts are worth their full army point value.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; Warcasters and warlocks are worth 5 army points each.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; If a list contains two or more multiple-model solos, all casualties are counted toward the same solo until it is completely destroyed.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>assassination_victory</anchor>    <name>Assassination Victory</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; When only one player owns warcasters/warlocks remaining in play, that player immediately wins the game. Conduct control point scoring upon an assassination victory. This scoring does not change game results (cannot lead to a scenario victory) but affects scoring the game. If all warcasters/warlocks are simultaneously destroyed, the game ends and victory is determined using tiebreakers.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>contest</anchor>    <name>Contest</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; A player must own at least one model within a zone, within 4? of a flag, or within 2? of an objective to contest that zone, flag, orobjective. Enemy objectives contest zones that they are within, flags within 4? and other objectives within 2?.Warcasters, warlocks, inertwarjacks, wild warbeasts, models that are fleeing, and models that are under an opponent’s control cannot contest. Enemy objectives cannot contest themselves.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>control</anchor>    <name>Control</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; A player cannot control a zone, flag, or objective that he dominates. See zone, flag, and objective descriptions for specific control requirements.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>deployment</anchor>    <name>Deployment</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Refer to the diagram in each scenario to set up a game. Each player’s board edge, deployment zone, objectives circle), flags (triangle) and zones will be highlighted in that player’s corresponding color (P1 = red, P2 = blue). Flags, zones, and objectives will be identified as friendly Faction, friendly, or enemy in the scenario rules.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>dominate</anchor>    <name>Dominate</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; A player dominates a zone if he owns one or more warcaster/warlock models within it and no opponent contests it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A player dominates a flag if he owns one or more warcaster/warlock models B2B with a flag that an opponent does not contest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A player dominates an objective if he owns one or more warcaster/warlock models within 2? of an objective that an opponent does not contest. Some scenarios add additional requirements for dominate. A warcaster/warlock (including units and those that consist of multiple models) cannot dominate more than one scenario element. When a warcaster/warlock would dominate more than one scenario element the active player must choose one to dominate. When two or more warcasters/warlocks would dominate the same zone, flag, or objective only the active player’s warcaster/warlock dominates.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>flag_40_mm_base</anchor>    <name>Flag (40 mm base)</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Incorporeal, stationary, immune to all game effects. They do not activate and cannot be targeted, damaged, moved, placed, or removed from play.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A player controls a flag if he owns one or more models that are not immobile, fleeing, wild, or inert B2B with a flag that an opponent does not contest. There are no additional requirements for solos, warjacks, or warbeasts. If the model B2B with the flag is a member of a unit, the unit must contain 50% or more of its starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must also be within 4? of the flag.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>kill_box</anchor>    <name>Kill Box</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Starting on the first player’s second turn, if a player ends his own turn with a friendly warcaster/warlock completely within 14?  of any board edge, his opponent immediately scores 2 control points. A player can measure 14? from any board edge during his warcaster/warlock’s activation.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>objective_50_mm_base</anchor>    <name>Objective (50 mm base)</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Objectives are a model type used only in scenarios. The rules for these models are on their corresponding objective cards. Objectives cannot be controlled (only dominated).  When an objective is friendly, or enemy, to all other models continuous effects are resolved on both players’ turns. Additionally, only the player who made the attack (or caused the continuous effect) that destroyed the objective earns the corresponding control points for its destruction.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>own</anchor>    <name>Own</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Players own the models in their fielded army list and any models created by abilities of models in the army list.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>scenario_element</anchor>    <name>Scenario Element</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Zones, flags, and objectives.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>scenario_victory</anchor>    <name>Scenario Victory</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; When a player has fulfilled the victory conditions described in the scenario, that player immediately wins the game.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>
    <anchor>solo</anchor>
    <name>Solo</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt;Points equal to the army point cost of the model. If a solo consists of multiple models, when counting army points ignore solos that have fewer than 50% (rounding up) of their starting number remaining in play. For doubling purposes all the remaining models must be within the designated area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exception – Feralgeist: If controlling a friendly warbeast use the warbeast’s point cost. If controlling an enemy warbeast place Feralgeist in B2B contact with the controlled warbeast, using the rule of least disturbance (WARMACHINE: Prime Mk II, p. 65) if necessary, then remove the warbeast from play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exception – Machine Wraith: If controlling a friendly warjack use the warjack’s point cost. If controlling an enemy warjack place Machine Wraith in B2B contact with the controlled warjack, using the rule of least disturbance (WARMACHINE: Prime Mk II, p. 65) if necessary&lt;/p&gt;</definition>
</term>
<term>    <anchor>starting_number</anchor>    <name>Starting number</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; The number of models that a model/unit starts with based on the point cost paid. Model/units that are discounted due to Theme Force rules always use their card’s listed point cost and model count for 3rd/4th tiebreaker scoring. Models that are added to an army list for free also use the card’s point cost and model count for 3rd/4th tiebreaker scoring.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>warcasters_warlocks</anchor>    <name>Warcasters/Warlocks</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; 5 points for each warcaster or warlock regardless of warjack and warbeast bonus points. Warcaster/warlocks consisting of multiple models with the warcaster/warlock type are worth only 5 points regardless of number remaining. Models automatically included with the warcaster or warlock without the warcaster or warlock subtype do not affect warcaster/warlock scoring. &lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>warjacks_warbeasts</anchor>    <name>Warjacks/Warbeasts</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; Points equal to the army point cost of the model.&lt;/p&gt; </definition></term>
<term>    <anchor>zone</anchor>    <name>Zone</name>  
    <definition>&lt;p&gt; A player controls a zone if he owns one or more models that are not immobile, fleeing, wild, or inert within it and no opponent contests it. There are no additional requirements for solos, warjacks or warbeasts.For a unit to control a zone the unit must contain 50% or more of its starting number (rounding up) and all those remaining models must be within the same zone.&lt;/p&gt; </definition>
</term>
</terms>